# Name: Tim Carr

#### Personal statement

My work background has been working in the accountancy profession. However, my love of all thing's tech meant I moved sideways into becoming the firm's IT department. This was both a staff and customer facing role. In addition to working with staff and customers I also dealt with suppliers, senior management, and business owners. During this time, I created the firm's intranet site. It was originally intended as a resource me but other staff in the company quickly caught onto its usefulness and so its scope was increased to include resources other staff wanted. I also taught myself VBA for Excel (the accountant's favourite spreadsheet). VBA allowed me to automate many regular tasks staff were carrying out. My knowledge in this area was self-taught and I was often left feeling there were better or easier ways to do things. This eventually led to me joining nology to fill in the gaps and expand my knowledge of web development.

Outside of work my hobbies of running and martial arts have led me to a number of activities working with children and adults. These include being an event and run director for my local junior parkrun. A guide runner with blind and visually impaired runners. Also, for a time I was a karate instructor with a local club, competing at our clubs local and national level competitions. I have now swapped the karate for volunteering once a week at a local animal rescue centre.

Both my work and hobbies have involved me in supervising and supporting individuals and groups to progress in their own knowledge and skills. I believe it is important to encourage others to realise they can do more than they thought possible.

## **Key Skills**

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- JavaScript, Rest API's,
- REACT
- Testing (Unit: Jest and End to end: Cypress)
- Node
- Typescript
- Angular
- Object Orientated Programming
- NPM, Postman, Git, Bash and GitHub
- UX and UI design
- Troubleshooting IT issues such as hardware, software, networking, and user training
- Microsoft products including Excel, Word and Outlook. Automation of Excel using VBA
- Knowledge of accounting systems and payroll software including Sage, Xero, QuickBooks and Payroll Manager
- Dealing with business transactions including
  - Banking payments
  - Credit card receipts
  - o Direct debit collections
  - Credit control

## **Employment History**

#### \_nology Trainee Software Developer

January 2021 - April 2021

Currently I am taking a 12 week intensive Software Development course. The course covers the fundamentals of HTML, CSS and JavaScript. We have also learnt about SCSS and BEM. We are now learning about REACT and putting this into practice on a 5 week project for an actual customer. All our coding involves the use of Git and GitHub to create versions and host our code as the course progresses.

### T and T Accounting Services Ltd, Sea Mills, Bristol

(July 2002 – Present)

This is a small business run by myself and my wife serving a small number of clients. Clients vary from individuals with some private income to a small company with £750k turnover

### Agency worker for Royal Mail

December 2020 – January 2021

#### The Real Olive Company Limited, Brentry, Bristol

(January 2019 – September 2020)

#### **Finance Manager**

(Contracted for maternity cover – extended due to Covid-19)

- Running the finance department
- Updating processes at the request of management
- Reporting to management
- Recruiting and supervising two members of staff for the department

#### Asda, Patchway, Bristol

(December 2018 – March 2019)

## **Home Grocery Deliveries**

### **Evans & Partners Limited, Kingswood, Bristol**

(September 1989 – September 2018)

#### **Practice Manager**

(May 2016 – September 2018)

### IT Manager

(Jan 2002 – April 2016)

#### Accountant

(September 1989 – December 2001)

#### **Education**

## \_nology Trainee Junior Software Developer

(2021)

#### **ICAEW**

(1989 –1995) ACA part qualified

### **University of Bristol**

(September 1986 – July 1989) BSc in Maths and Physics

#### **Hobbies & Interests**

- Running
  - o Guide runner for visually impaired runners VI Runners Bristol
  - Member of local running club Westbury Harriers
  - o Co Event Director and Run Director for Kings Weston junior parkrun
  - o Took part in the Kx365 challenge in 2015 to run or walk 5k every day of the year
  - o Participate in races and events with distances from 5k to Ultra's.
  - Looking forward to trying my first Backyard Ultra later this year which is a "last man standing" style of event.
- Volunteer at Holly Hedge animal sanctuary
- Karate, student from 2011 and instructor from 2013 (retired from both 2016)

#### References

References are available upon request.